have you ever been in a situation where your
database queries are slow and you need to speed
them up while keeping costs down I'd like you
to imagine for a moment you've built a movie
streaming platform that is growing quickly when
you started you decided to use mongodb to store
and retrieve movies this worked really well for
a while and now things are starting to break down
you've already attempted to optimize your queries
to mongodb and you are able to squeak out a little
more performance but it wasn't enough you know you
need to Cache your queries in redis but you want
to make sure you keep costs down this is where the
cache aside pattern comes in handy the goal of the
cache aside pattern is to set up optimal caching
for data retrieval on demand so rather than
syncing your entire database with redis from the
start you'll fill redis as your data is requested
when an application requests data you first see
if that data exists in redis if it exists you can
quickly return it if it doesn't exist you fetch
the data from your database and store it in redis
for future requests then return the data to the
application let's see how you might implement the
cache aside pattern in code here I'm using node.js
with the mongodb client and the redisome library
first I'll create a function to create a hash
key based on the search criteria this will be
used to store and retrieve Keys from redis next
I'll create a function to find the top movies
in it I'll get my [ __ ] and redis connections
then create my search criteria for now I'm
looking for movies in English that have an
IMDb rating greater than or equal to 8.5
now I need to get the hash
key to use to search redis
if I find a value in redis then I log the cache
hit and return the value if I don't find the
value in redis I log a cache Miss and then search
mongodb for the movies finally I store the results
from mongodb in redis making sure to expire
them after 30 seconds and return the results
let's run this function twice to
see if we get the expected result
when I run the script you can see I first
get a cache Miss then a subsequent cash hit
this is the expected result since we
started with nothing in our redis database
in redis Insight you'll see our stored string with
the expiration date when I click the value you can
see the stringified result for mongodb even though
this is a string I can inform redis Insight that
I'm looking at Json and it will display it in a
format that is easier to read if you plan to use
the cache aside pattern and store your queries in
redis as strings one thing you'll need to decide
on your own is how frequently you want to expire
the data you don't want the expiration time to be
too short but if it's too long it can lead to
data consistency problems one way to solve the
data consistency issue is to use another pattern
called the right behind or right through pattern
this is something that I will discuss in a future
video however another way to mitigate some of the
data consistency issues is to get more granular
with how you store and retrieve data from redis
with redis stack you can Store and search Json
documents in redis so we can rewrite our code
to Store and search redis just like we do with
mongodb let's look at what that might look like
here I'm using node.js like before only
this time I'm creating a movie collection
in redis using redisome each movie will have
the same fields that I'm storing in mongodb
to find the top movies I first get my mongodb
and redis connections then I get the redis movie
Repository next I search the repository for
movies in English with an IMDb rating greater
than or equal to 8.5 the result will always
be an array so for my purposes I'm comfortable
saying that if the array is not empty then
it's a cash hit otherwise it's a cache Miss
for cash misses I get the results from
mongodb then I iterate over the results
and store each value in redis you see here
that I didn't set an expiration on my data
for this to work you'll need to determine the
best time to delete the data from the cache
typically what people do is delete the data in
redis whenever they delete or update it in mongodb
let's run the fine top movies function
twice and see if we get the expected results
when I run the script I first get a
cache Miss then a subsequent cash hit
this is expected since we started
with nothing in our redis database
looking at our data in redis Insight you
can see we now have a collection of movie
Json documents instead of before where we
only had a single key with a string value
note that there is no expiration on the movie
documents this is because our application will
take care of deleting and updating these
documents whenever they change in mongodb
if I click on a movie document you can see that
it is storing all of the movie information that
we defined in our schema remember the cache aside
pattern is useful when you need to query data
frequently and want to fill your cache on demand
to save on cost if you're interested in learning
more about storing and searching Master data
in redis check out our ebook that covers three
design patterns to speed up mirn applications
the link is in the description down below
foreign [Music]